### PRODUCT MANAGER

**Executive Summary** 

Unique Qualifications Product Specialist - Sprayer - Springfield, IL #6680 Raised & worked on a corn, soybean, wheat and livestock farm in Central Illinois Farm, Farm Supply, Agronomic, Precision Ag, Farm Equipment business experience Certified Crop Adviser (CCA) since 1994; Agronomy trainer 1993-94 International agriculture experience: across the U.S., Canada & Brazil Extensive presentation and communication experience; from farmers to corporate exec.'s

Professional Experience

Product Manager

January 2002 to Current Motorola Solutions il/4 Bogota, NJ

- Develop business case, plan & coordinate product strategy and development for sprayers, floaters & precision ag systems for 3 brands.
- Review regularly with executives Supervise Market Research conduct interviews and forums with large farmers Coordinate development team including Marketing, Engineering, & Manufacturing groups Evaluate products and benchmark to competitive products Cultivate & manage strategic partners on corporate level Internal promotion of product line, secure development funds, financial planning, etc.
- Serve as Agronomic & Precision Ag expert for CNH Application Equipment division.
- Global responsibility limited international travel (products marketed in 11+ countries).

## Regional Sales Manager

November 1999 to January 2002 Schwan's Company il/4 Los Banos, CA

- Supervised largest market segment (60% of sales) through period of growth.
- Managed 4 large independent distributors, their 100+ dealers & customers throughout the upper Midwest.
- Assist with large farmer & dealer calls.
- Assist distributors with sales to National & Regional accounts at executive levels.
- Serve as Agronomic & Precision Ag expert for CNH Application Equip.
- division.

## Precision Ag Manager

November 1997 to November 1999 CNH i1/4 City, STATE

- Hired by Tyler Industries, purchased by Case, then by New Holland/Fiat; successfully thriving through the corporate changes.
- Served on Transition Team from Tyler to Case IH products & processes.
- Provide company vision for, and developed, Case IH's Application Equipment Precision Ag program and products.
- Convinced distributor network to create new "Precision Ag" departments Develop & maintain strategic partners at the corporate level Assist distributor sales to Nat'l.
- amp; Regn'l.
- accounts at executive level, and to large farmers Coordinate product research, selection, pricing and system integration Liaison to Midwestern universities (including Illinois & Purdue) for Precision Ag.

## Agronomist / Precision Ag Manager

March 1993 to November 1997 Total Soil Management TSM Services il/4 City, STATE

- Agronomic consultant for soil fertility, advising large farmers & dealers in NE  $\hat{A}^{1}_{4}$  of the U.S.
- Agronomy trainer for 1st & 2nd round of Certified Crop Advisor (CCA) testing Established Precision Ag division of company, "Agri-Data Management".
- Provide vision for, and developed business plan for new concept of Precision Ag.
- Promoted, sold & supported Precision Ag practices & products from ID.
- to MA.
- GPS mapped and soil sampled tens of thousands of acres from MO.
- to NY.
- Sold new concept to large farmers & dealers based on short & long term potentials.
- Develop GIS mapping service: product development, staffing; marketing.
- Developed & maintained farm & industry contacts regionally & nationally Established & maintained business relationships with executives of partners.

# Agronomy, Sales & Operations Manager

March 1984 to March 1993 Growmark Vermilion Service Co.-FS i1/4 City, STATE

- Supervising sales & operations of Crop Production department (fertilizer, crop protection products, seed, fuel (including ethanol).
- Marketing plan development & implementation Managed up to 13 salesmen in 4 dept.'s; 30 operations personnel; sales to 600+ farmers
   Resident Agronomic expert; implemented agronomic, sales, safety & operational training.
- Supervise & assist with agronomic advising & sales to large & commercial accounts Managed Fuel & LP Gas forward contracting
  programs Purchased most product for resale & equipment for respective departments Won Annual Sales Program 5 of 8 years; Company
  won sales growth awards in '90 & '91 Worked with Board of Directors totransition through 2 management changes.

## Crops Specialist & Plant Manager

September 1979 to March 1984 Growmark Corn Belt FS i1/4 City, STATE

- Agronomic sales & service to farmers of plant food, seed and crop protection products for areas largest farm supply outlet Plant & operations manager for product sold to 125+ customers on 75,000+ acres.
- Focused on large farmers & corporate customers Performed Agronomic recommendations & crop diagnostic field scouting Supervised record keeping & billing system Supervised sales & operations staff of 5-20, & contracted custom applicator Won Annual Sales Program Award 3 of 4 years eligible.

## Sales & Management Trainee

May 1978 to September 1979 Growmark Kankakee Service Co.-FS i1/4 City, STATE

- Plant operations at central facility servicing two fertilizer outlets.
- · Seed Sales Mgr.
- supervise & motivate farmer dealers.
- Manage seed orders/inventory.
- Supervise operations staff.
- Responsible for central warehousing of seed, feed, chemicals, and petroleum products.

#### Education

B.A: Agri-Business Management, 1978 University of Illinois Agri-Business Management

Numerous Certified Crop Advisor (CCA) Training & CEU seminars CNH's "Principles of Finance for Managers"; Growmark's "Management Training" series "Strategic Agri-Marketing" Seminar - Purdue University Center for Agri-Business Growmark Professional Sales Training series Interests

Family activities; physical fitness; church & community service; sports, landscaping Additional Information

• Interests Family activities; physical fitness; church & community service; sports, landscaping

## Skills

billing system, Develop business, business plan, CCA, competitive, concept, consultant, Data Management, fertilizer, Finance, financial planning, funds, GIS, GPS, inventory, MA, Management Training, Marketing plan development, Market Research, marketing, market, network, personnel, pricing, processes, product development, product research, promotion, record keeping, safety, Sales, Sales Mgr, Sales Training, seminars, staffing, Strategic, strategy and development, Supervising, system integration, trainer, vision, warehousing